

# SALMAN F. RAHMAN STUDENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING



# CONTACT



**Phone** 

01300192216



**Email** 

salman.f.rahman@g.bracu.ac.bd



**Github** 

https://github.com/Salman-Farid



**Address** 

Dhap EngineerPara, Rangpur, Bangladesh 5401



# **EDUCATION**

2020 - 2024
Studying in Bachelor Of Computer
Science & Engineering (Final year)
Brac University

**2018** 

HSC

Rangpur Government College, Rangpur

② 2016 SSC

Rangpur Zilla School, Rangpur



## LANGUAGE

- Enalish
- Bengali
- Hindi



## **PROFILE INFO**

Driven software developer with proficiency in Python, C++, Java, Css, Html, Javascript, Dart and data analysis tools (Excel VBA, SQL, Power BI). Proven ability to design, develop, and implement software solutions, leveraging strong problemsolving and analytical skills. Passionate about continuous learning and fostering effective communication within teams.



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**



## **Software Developer**

2023-2024

Working as a Software Developer and my services include creating custom software solutions, developing mobile apps, and providing ongoing maintenance and support. I help organizations and businesses achieve their goals through the use of software. Working in Upwork, Fiverr & Local Organizations.

# Q/A Expert

2022-2023

Worked as a Q/A Expert for less than 1 year in Photomath



# **MY SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

- Highly skilled in Python, C++, Java, Css, Html, Javascript, Dart & flutter framework.
- Skilled in Machine learning & tools(tensorflow, pytorch, scikit-learn, keras, XGBoost, LightGBM, CatBoost, sklearn, etc.)
- Strong background in computer science, math, statistics and English writing
- Data Analysis: Microsoft Excel(Including VBA), MS Access, Microsoft Power BI, SQL, Python, Google Analytics.
- Office Application: MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, MS Access, MS Project
- Interpersonal skills & Interests: Empathetic, Self-motivated, Team-worker, Good Listener, Learning new things & highly passionate about desktop & mobile application building.

Software Development

Computer Science

Database Management

Math/Statistics/English



## **PROJECT & RELEVANT ACTIVITIES:**

- Created Application for Organizations Management (TManageHub).
- Admin dashboard, User Dashboard, Payment Dashboard, Attendance Performance Tarcking, Profile Disable/Enable, Profile Approve Screen Youtube link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IYGNzz1D4jM&ab\_channel=FlutterGang
- $\bullet\;$  Build community service project (Walpaper App, Food App , Quiz App)
- Build Banking system & University Management system using Java
- Leadership role as the president of the school's environmental club & University
- Volunteer & presenter at a School & University



## **PERSONAL STATEMENT:**

I am a highly motivated and passionate individual with strong background in programming, math and software development. My education and diverse experiences have allowed me to develop a wide range of skills and I am committed to continuous learning and personal growth. And excited to apply my knowledge and skills to contribute to a company's success and growth.



## MY REFERENCE

## **Md Rafigul Alam**

Joint Director, Bangladesh Bank, Dhaka. Mobile: +8801721542211, Email: rafiqul.alam@bb.org.bd

# Saidur Rahman Sayeed

Officer, Ansar vdb unnayan Bank, Dhaka. Mobile: +8801770872255, Email: srahman1705@gmail.com